Allan Burns

9 Murphy Court, Newton, MA 02458

870-270-7438 SOFTWARE ENGINEER allanlburns@gmail.com https://github.com/allanlburns

Proficient and solutions-oriented Software Engineer with hands-on experience developing web-based applications individually and as part of a team. Demonstrate strong analytical and problem-solving skills as well as a knack for learning and utilizing different programming languages and technologies (Python, Flask, React, React Native, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Bootstrap). Familiar with agile methodology and able to introduce best practices into the process.

- Proficient as a Software Programmer using Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, React.js, HTML5
- Experience in object-oriented programming (OOP) concepts using Python, Ruby and JavaScript
- Expert knowledge of and experience in Object-Oriented Design and Programming Algorithms.
- Used Python for data analytics, data wrangling and extracting data using Pandas, NumPy and SciPy

TECHNICAL SKILLS

	SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS
Cloud Technology Software	Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) UNIX, Linux
	Photoshop, Gimp, Agile Software Development, Scrum, Data Modeler, Unit Testing
Tools/Methodologies	GitHub, Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook, Atom, Sublime Text
Database	SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, MongoDB, NoSQL
	React.js, React Native, Ruby on Rails, Docker, Docker Hub, AWS
Web Technologies/Development Frameworks	Flask, Django, NumPy, Pandas, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, BootstrapUI,
Programming Languages	Python, Ruby, Java, JavaScript, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, TypeScript

- Web scraper project for shoe outlet sales website using BeautifulSoup, Scrapy, and Discord API.
- Ecommerce Site-Capstone project for a comic book store where users can view and order products, pay for
 purchases through the **Stripe** payment integration, check upcoming new releases and cultivate their in-store
 subscription list built-in **Flask, Python, Bootstrap, SQL,** and **numerous APIs.**
- Car Dealership Site-A website for car dealerships to track, view, and update customer maintenance records. It is built using **Python**, **Flask**, **Bootstrap**, and **SQLite**.
- Social Media Site-A social media site where users can upload written content and pictures, follow other users, and comment on their posts. It is built with **Ruby**, **Ruby on Rails**, **SQL**, and **Bootstrap**.
- Video Showcase-A website to spotlight users' favorite YouTube videos. Users can create categories and add and remove videos. Built-in **Django** and incorporates **YouTube API** and **AJAX**.
- Alien Invasion-Arcade game similar to Space Invaders. The player controls ships and destroys incoming alien ships
 Built-In Python with the Pygame library.
- Real Estate Site-A listing of real estate offerings, searchable by city, state, keywords, or price range. Features a contact page with automated email notification. Built-in **Python, Django, Jinja**, and **Bootstrap.**
- Log Analyzer-A simple tool to quickly scan .txt log files of tens of thousands of lines and deliver readout of errors found. It was scripted in **Python** and **Regex**.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Acrolinx, Burlington/Waltham, MA *Software Support Engineer*

09/2018-present

- Troubleshoot and resolve software platform issues for SaaS customers including Microsoft, Amazon, Google, and IBM
- Reproduce customer issues with usage of Acrolinx Core Platform and integrations on Linux VMs and implement solutions
- Investigate logs from product server and client integration and monitor performance telemetry in Datadog
- Collaborate with integration developers on regular conference calls to discuss bug-related tickets
- Escalate deeper software issues to Berlin-based developer teams through JIRA tickets
- Assemble customer-unique linguistic resource guidance packages in Jenkins and install on customer servers

- Install PingFederate on customer cloud servers for SSO
- Migrate customer data, configurations, users, and terminology to new or additional servers.
- Set up, configure, and maintain Robin Powered office resource management software
- Facilitate updates, maintenance, and new instance creation of Rackspace-managed AWS servers for customers' cloud-based Acrolinx server installations

CODING TEMPLE - Boston, MA

09/2019-present

Software Engineer

- Developed full-stack web applications using Flask, Python, React.js, SQL, HTML/CSS, and JavaScript. Included in the
 applications built are custom designed relational databases, user role management, and salted hashing password encryption
 for site security.
- Developed web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, Django, and SQL
- Developed dynamic frontend and backend applications using Python, Flask, and Django Frameworks
- Data Analysis, Data Wrangling, and the development of algorithms in Python for data mining and analysis
- Python NumPy, SciPy, Pandas packages to perform dataset manipulation
- Utilized Native React to develop mobile applications and web bootstrap with React.js
- Utilized CSS to make the application responsive Designed and developed the UI of the website using HTML, AJAX, CSS and JavaScript

Commonwealth Financial Network, Waltham, MA

07/2017-09/2018

Desktop Support Specialist

- Configured laptops for and set up workstations for new hires
- Imaged computers for redeployment
- Troubleshoot hardware problems and responded to tickets from ServiceNow ticketing system
- Set up conference rooms for teleconference using Vidyo software and hardware
- Updated hardware assets in an asset management system
- Configured and shipped firewalls to CFN-affiliated advisors

The Cambridge Institute for International Education, Waltham, MA

04/2015-06/2017

Service Desk Analyst

- Maintained and supported marketing department's PHP/WordPress website
- Created and updated new users in Active Directory, Exchange Server, and Office 365
- Imaged and configured computers for new hires and replacement workstations
- Manage compliance, maintenance, reimaging, and asset management of company cell phones
- Respond to and process Service Desk tickets for office-based users and remote staff via VPN
- Facilitated northeast region's weekly conference call with 20+ remote staff members through Adobe Connect, Skype for Business, and Zoom software
- Spearheaded host document registry project during the company's transition from Google to Microsoft services by collaborating with the accounting and IT departments on the cloud storage solution

EDUCATION

Boston University, Boston, MA

Master of Education in Teaching English as a Second Language (TESOL), GPA 3.70

Jan. 2014

University of Central Arkansas, Conway, AR

Master of Arts in History, GPA 4.0 Bachelor of Arts in History, minor in German, GPA 4.0 Aug. 2009

Dec. 2006